<folderSkill repo="itch_games" root="R:\itch_games" path="unsoccer">
  <parent path="../skill.md" />
  <parent path="../skill.xml" />
  <parent path="../itch_games.skill.md" />
  <entry file="unsoccer.skill.md" />
  <runtime url="https://io-games.mecharulez.com/unsoccer/" />
  <version current="v0.0.014" />
  <publicSurface owner="UI Designer" localUrl="http://127.0.0.1:8000/unsoccer/" itchEntry="dist/index.html">
    <rule>unsoccer/index.html is the public static page for the local server and production route until the built client is deployed there.</rule>
    <rule>UI Designer owns public page hierarchy, prototype status copy, catalog continuity, and itch.io presentation fit.</rule>
    <rule>The public route must not expose a directory listing.</rule>
  </publicSurface>
  <files>
    <file path="index.html" role="public-page prototype-status" />
    <folder path="client" role="browser-client" />
    <file path="client/index.html" role="client-entry hud-settings-dom" />
    <file path="client/src/main.ts" role="three-runtime hud-settings-network-input" />
    <file path="client/src/styles.css" role="hud-settings-responsive-css" />
    <file path="client/src/settings.ts" role="ui-settings-persistence-validation" />
    <file path="client/src/input-map.ts" role="input-remap-movement-resolution" />
    <file path="client/src/audio.ts" role="procedural-web-audio-runtime" />
    <file path="client/src/weather.ts" role="weather-graphics-options" />
    <folder path="server" role="authoritative-server" />
    <folder path="shared" role="shared-protocol" />
    <folder path="assets" role="runtime-assets-and-provenance" />
  </files>
  <rules>
    <rule>Client bundles must not import server-only code.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.002 keeps Russian player-facing text, HDR-style environment lighting, a visible sun, a 120-second realtime day cycle, an inertial perspective follow camera, and distinct server-authoritative body/left-foot/right-foot contacts.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.003 keeps weather and hazards server-authoritative; any puddle, slush, or snowbank that changes movement or ball physics must also be visible in the client.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.007 aligns public client/server version and keeps production transport dependency-free: built-in Node WebSocket JSON plus HTTP polling fallback.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.008 keeps the version and client weight always visible and starts the residential courtyard visual pass around the snowy field.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.008 audio uses a server-authored audioEvents ring buffer in ServerState so roster, kick/body, goal, and countdown cues synchronize across WebSocket and HTTP fallback clients by authoritative event id.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 expands the runtime Art Director pass with courtyard models, procedural animated footballer rigs, visible sun/moon/orbit marker, ambient/bounce lighting, and QA-readable art/day-cycle datasets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 makes WASD team-relative, keeps local controlled movement responsive with a short client prediction lead, and removes artificial pitch bounds from player movement.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 ships the UI Designer runtime pass with redesigned HUD hierarchy, event/status/network panels, toolbar buttons, settings modal tabs, localStorage settings, remappable input, runtime audio/graphics/network/accessibility controls, and QA-readable UI debug datasets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.010 is the unified 0010 release build with all current runtime workstreams, a camera-framed sun/moon marker, synchronized version surfaces, and repo-side publication evidence.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.011 doubles the field/courtyard, starts authoritative time at 06:00, rotates sun/moon by server day time, randomizes weather every 60-120s, adds dawn birds/day traffic audio, moving cars, sprint/stamina/exhaustion/jump, foot/hand/head player hits, bouncier ball physics, thicker goal rebounds, local cloth net ripples, and 10 local Free3D vertex-color soccer-ball GLBs.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.012 keeps the current scene size, fixes server-driven day cycle under qaTime=0, makes 04:00-20:00 bright daytime and 20:00-04:00 the dark window, hides the old sun-path debug line, prevents clear weather precipitation particles, weights random weather toward clear/dawn, upgrades the goal net to client-only Verlet cloth, shows the active Free3D vertex-color GLB ball on-field while hiding that rack variant, aligns visible goal posts with thicker server colliders, and acceptance-tests post rebounds plus bouncier heading physics.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.013 replaces the primary primitive player body with a local Free3D Online 6300420 skinned GLB character optimized to 2.09 MB, cloned with SkeletonUtils, animated with per-player AnimationMixer, and keeps procedural primitives only as loading/error fallback.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.014 replaces the white all-animation character runtime with a different textured Free3D 6299851 split pipeline: rigged_unity.glb, WebP albedo/normal/ORM maps, and separate FBX idle/walk/run/jump clips selected by player state.</rule>
    <rule>Server-confirmed left-foot, hand, head, jump, and body contacts must stay visually distinguishable and expose data-last-action-kind, data-last-action-player, and data-last-action-at for QA.</rule>
    <rule>Server owns physics, score, teams, and room assignment.</rule>
    <rule>Production transport is plain WebSocket JSON under /unsoccer/socket/ with HTTP polling fallback, implemented with built-in Node http/net/crypto primitives; do not require geckos.io, ws, or native node-datachannel on the Qwertystock host.</rule>
    <rule>UNSOCCER_TEST_MODE enables /api/test/* only for isolated local acceptance and must not be exposed in production.</rule>
    <rule>npm run test:unsoccer:acceptance is the deterministic gate for spectator roles, team-relative WASD movement, HTTP fallback join/input/state, pitch-bound freedom, foot/hand/head kicks, jump, sprint/stamina, weather, goal reset, and server audioEvents.</rule>
    <rule>Acceptance derives the expected version from package.json.games.unsoccer.version and must not hard-code a release string.</rule>
    <rule>npm run package:unsoccer rebuilds before creating dist/unsoccer-itch.zip so stale dist output is not published.</rule>
    <rule>Client audio is procedural Web Audio driven by authoritative ServerState audioEvents and weather state, not local input prediction.</rule>
    <rule>Audio QA must inspect data-audio-played-events, data-audio-blocked-events, data-audio-context, and data-audio-unlocked after a real trusted browser gesture.</rule>
    <rule>First 4 clients are players; clients 5-32 are spectators/testers.</rule>
    <rule>Itch package contains static built client only.</rule>
    <rule>Free3D runtime assets require local GLB files and provenance; tokenless LowPoly 1k assets must be selected only from exact public worker inventory paths.json entries.</rule>
  </rules>
</folderSkill>
