<folderSkill repo="itch_games" root="R:\itch_games" path="unsoccer">
  <parent path="../skill.md" />
  <parent path="../skill.xml" />
  <parent path="../itch_games.skill.md" />
  <entry file="unsoccer.skill.md" />
  <runtime url="https://io-games.mecharulez.com/unsoccer/" />
  <version current="v0.0.003" />
  <publicSurface owner="UI Designer" localUrl="http://127.0.0.1:8000/unsoccer/" itchEntry="dist/index.html">
    <rule>unsoccer/index.html is the public static page for the local server and production route until the built client is deployed there.</rule>
    <rule>UI Designer owns public page hierarchy, prototype status copy, catalog continuity, and itch.io presentation fit.</rule>
    <rule>The public route must not expose a directory listing.</rule>
  </publicSurface>
  <files>
    <file path="index.html" role="public-page prototype-status" />
    <folder path="client" role="browser-client" />
    <file path="client/src/audio.ts" role="procedural-web-audio-runtime" />
    <folder path="server" role="authoritative-server" />
    <folder path="shared" role="shared-protocol" />
    <folder path="assets" role="runtime-assets-and-provenance" />
  </files>
  <rules>
    <rule>Client bundles must not import server-only code.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.002 keeps Russian player-facing text, HDR-style environment lighting, a visible sun, a 120-second realtime day cycle, an inertial perspective follow camera, and distinct server-authoritative body/left-foot/right-foot contacts.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.003 keeps weather and hazards server-authoritative; any puddle, slush, or snowbank that changes movement or ball physics must also be visible in the client.</rule>
    <rule>Server owns physics, score, teams, and room assignment.</rule>
    <rule>UNSOCCER_TEST_MODE enables /api/test/* only for isolated local acceptance and must not be exposed in production.</rule>
    <rule>npm run test:unsoccer:acceptance is the deterministic gate for spectator roles, kicks, body contact, and goal reset.</rule>
    <rule>Client audio is procedural Web Audio driven by authoritative ServerState diffs, not local input prediction.</rule>
    <rule>First 4 clients are players; clients 5-32 are spectators/testers.</rule>
    <rule>Itch package contains static built client only.</rule>
    <rule>Free3D runtime assets require local GLB files and provenance.</rule>
  </rules>
</folderSkill>
