<folderSkill repo="itch_games" root="R:\itch_games" path="unsoccer">
  <parent path="../skill.md" />
  <parent path="../skill.xml" />
  <parent path="../itch_games.skill.md" />
  <entry file="unsoccer.skill.md" />
  <runtime url="https://io-games.mecharulez.com/unsoccer/" />
  <version current="v0.0.052" />
  <publicSurface owner="UI Designer" localUrl="http://127.0.0.1:8000/unsoccer/" itchEntry="dist/index.html">
    <rule>unsoccer/index.html is the public static page for the local server and production route until the built client is deployed there.</rule>
    <rule>UI Designer owns public page hierarchy, prototype status copy, catalog continuity, and itch.io presentation fit.</rule>
    <rule>The public route must not expose a directory listing.</rule>
  </publicSurface>
  <files>
    <file path="index.html" role="public-page prototype-status" />
    <folder path="client" role="browser-client" />
    <file path="client/index.html" role="client-entry hud-settings-dom" />
    <file path="client/character-controller-test.html" role="local-character-controller-test-page" />
    <file path="client/public/bot-tuning.html" role="static-server-bot-tuning-page" />
    <file path="client/public/game-settings.html" role="static-runtime-game-settings-admin-page" />
    <file path="client/public/game-admin.html" role="static-schema-runtime-game-admin-page" />
    <file path="client/src/main.ts" role="three-runtime hud-settings-network-input" />
    <file path="client/src/environment-props.ts" role="art-director-courtyard-free3d-environment-loader" />
    <file path="client/src/character-controller.ts" role="free3d-character-loader-animation-controller-ik" />
    <file path="client/src/character-controller-test.ts" role="standalone-character-controller-test-runtime" />
    <file path="client/src/styles.css" role="hud-settings-responsive-css" />
    <file path="client/src/settings.ts" role="ui-settings-persistence-validation" />
    <file path="client/src/input-map.ts" role="input-remap-movement-resolution" />
    <file path="client/src/audio.ts" role="procedural-web-audio-runtime" />
    <file path="client/src/weather.ts" role="weather-graphics-options" />
    <folder path="server" role="authoritative-server" />
    <folder path="shared" role="shared-protocol" />
    <file path="game-settings.json" role="runtime-game-settings-json-source" />
    <folder path="assets" role="runtime-assets-and-provenance" />
    <file path="client/public/assets/environment/free3d/roster.json" role="local-free3d-environment-runtime-roster" />
    <file path="assets/models/environment/free3d/provenance.json" role="local-free3d-environment-source-provenance" />
  </files>
  <rules>
    <rule>Client bundles must not import server-only code.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.002 keeps Russian player-facing text, HDR-style environment lighting, a visible sun, a 120-second realtime day cycle, an inertial perspective follow camera, and distinct server-authoritative body/left-foot/right-foot contacts.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.003 keeps weather and hazards server-authoritative; any puddle, slush, or snowbank that changes movement or ball physics must also be visible in the client.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.007 aligns public client/server version and keeps production transport dependency-free: built-in Node WebSocket JSON plus HTTP polling fallback.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.008 keeps the version and client weight always visible and starts the residential courtyard visual pass around the snowy field.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.008 audio uses a server-authored audioEvents ring buffer in ServerState so roster, kick/body, goal, and countdown cues synchronize across WebSocket and HTTP fallback clients by authoritative event id.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 expands the runtime Art Director pass with courtyard models, procedural animated footballer rigs, visible sun/moon/orbit marker, ambient/bounce lighting, and QA-readable art/day-cycle datasets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 makes WASD team-relative, keeps local controlled movement responsive with a short client prediction lead, and removes artificial pitch bounds from player movement.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.009 ships the UI Designer runtime pass with redesigned HUD hierarchy, event/status/network panels, toolbar buttons, settings modal tabs, localStorage settings, remappable input, runtime audio/graphics/network/accessibility controls, and QA-readable UI debug datasets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.010 is the unified 0010 release build with all current runtime workstreams, a camera-framed sun/moon marker, synchronized version surfaces, and repo-side publication evidence.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.011 doubles the field/courtyard, starts authoritative time at 06:00, rotates sun/moon by server day time, randomizes weather every 60-120s, adds dawn birds/day traffic audio, moving cars, sprint/stamina/exhaustion/jump, foot/hand/head player hits, bouncier ball physics, thicker goal rebounds, local cloth net ripples, and 10 local Free3D vertex-color soccer-ball GLBs.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.012 keeps the current scene size, fixes server-driven day cycle under qaTime=0, makes 04:00-20:00 bright daytime and 20:00-04:00 the dark window, hides the old sun-path debug line, prevents clear weather precipitation particles, weights random weather toward clear/dawn, upgrades the goal net to client-only Verlet cloth, shows the active Free3D vertex-color GLB ball on-field while hiding that rack variant, aligns visible goal posts with thicker server colliders, and acceptance-tests post rebounds plus bouncier heading physics.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.013 replaces the primary primitive player body with a local Free3D Online 6300420 skinned GLB character optimized to 2.09 MB, cloned with SkeletonUtils, animated with per-player AnimationMixer, and keeps procedural primitives only as loading/error fallback.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.014 replaces the white all-animation character runtime with a different textured Free3D 6299851 split pipeline: rigged_unity.glb, WebP albedo/normal/ORM maps, and separate FBX idle/walk/run/jump clips selected by player state.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.015 extracts the skinned character runtime into client/src/character-controller.ts, adds character-controller-test.html, blends idle/walk/run/jump by velocity with hysteresis/time scaling, applies procedural bone-IK strike overlays, extends the authoritative day cycle to 300 seconds, shortens true dark hours to 23:00-03:00, and adds four night-only floodlight masts with local volumetric beam meshes.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.016 halves goal post and crossbar radius, switches posts to neutral light metal, scores goals only on front goal-line plane crossing from the field side, rejects back-net entries, and adds clear center-circle, center-spot, penalty-box, goal-area, and penalty-spot markings.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.017 adds the local stamina HUD meter with state colors/labels, exposes local stamina datasets, and makes hand hits readable with a longer orange strike trail plus hand-action datasets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.017 character input/strike correction uses middle mouse button for head hits, prevents mouse wheel from triggering attacks, sends foot/hand ball impulses forward along player yaw from the limb-specific contact point, and alternates hand-hit visual/contact side without adding a new network KickKind.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.018 keeps the camera anchored to the controlled player with smoothed velocity lead, removes ball-driven camera drift, and adds HUD offscreen arrows for the ball and other players.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.018 character roster extension expanded the local runtime roster with skinned character controllers and FBX idle/walk/run/jump clips; current runtime policy supersedes the old textured pipeline.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.019 extends local-only goal nets into closed cages with back, roof, left-side, and right-side Verlet panels per goal while keeping net motion off the network.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.020 halves the authoritative shared BALL_RADIUS from 0.48 to 0.24 so the server collider, visible client ball, Free3D ball scale, sideline rack, and acceptance fixtures stay in sync.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.021 delays goal reset: 5 seconds of scoring-team celebration, then a 1-second server-authored ball return to kickoff before countdown; never teleport the ball to center immediately after a goal.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.021 balances the half-size ball with BALL_DENSITY 3.6 and lower normal hit impulses; acceptance guards against runaway projectile speeds.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.022 retargets Free3D character hand-strike IK so alternating hand hits keep logical left/right side, compensate mirrored roster arm bones, and punch forward at upper-chest/shoulder height with matching raised hand flash/trail.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.022 smooths authoritative keyboard movement: raw axes ramp, released axes decay, opposite axes take over faster, and controlled velocity accelerates/brakes; client prediction mirrors this and exposes data-movement-smoothing, data-local-move-speed, and data-local-move-axis for QA.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.023 assigns newly joined players random ready characters from CHARACTER_ROSTER through a shuffled non-repeating server deck and preserves player.characterId during role/team rebalancing.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.024 uses team-colored ground indicator rings and halos under players; browser QA exposes data-local-team-marker and data-local-team-marker-color for the local player.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.024 adds jumpRun for sprint/high-velocity jumps; until dedicated run-jump FBX clips are added to the runtime roster, jumpRun clones the normal jump clip and applies a stronger forward-leap IK overlay exposed through data-player-rig-jump-style=run.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.025 follows a lerped authoritative player offset for camera position/look target instead of skinned mesh or bone transforms; browser QA exposes data-camera-anchor-smoothing, data-camera-anchor-offset, and data-camera-follow-speed.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.025 activates server-authored player.ragdoll/ragdollAt when stamina reaches zero: sprint exhaustion preserves movement inertia, stamina-emptying hits apply heavy knockback/lift, local prediction must not override ragdoll snapshots, and browser QA exposes data-player-rig-ragdoll plus data-local-player-ragdoll.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.026 widens night floodlight coverage with broader SpotLight beams, larger volumetric cones, per-mast white-temperature variation, and subtle deterministic flicker exposed through data-stadium-light-beam-angle, data-stadium-light-beam-radius, data-stadium-light-palette, and data-stadium-light-flicker.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.027 makes player-ball contact height-aware: body bumps require vertical body overlap, foot/hand/head hits require vertical reach, jumps can clear ground balls, and unreachable high balls cannot be headed.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.028 extends the residential courtyard with outer roads, sidewalks, dense procedural props, and 8 local Free3D environment GLB asset sources cloned into 100+ environment instances; browser QA exposes data-environment-model-instances, data-procedural-environment-instances, data-free3d-environment-instances, data-free3d-environment-asset-count, and data-free3d-environment-loaded.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.029 doubles ordinary foot/hand/head ball-hit power and adds server-authored LMB left-foot charge from 2x tap power to 4x full power over one second; held charge may fire once on ball contact before release and browser QA exposes data-local-kick-charge.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.029 widens gameplay camera framing and adds close sideline pennant/bench strips so the dense v0.0.028 courtyard dressing is visible in normal play while the pitch remains clear.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.030 makes striking more user-friendly: foot/hand/head ball hits have player-centered assist reach, LMB clicks buffer for a short contact window, active strike inputs suppress same-frame body bump, and body-only ball contact is smaller, softer, and less frequent.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.031 adds server-authoritative bot actors that fill active player slots to four, remove/backfill as humans join or leave, do not consume connectedClients capacity, expose controller=bot in snapshots, play through normal movement/combat/scoring rules, and can be tuned from client/public/bot-tuning.html through /api/bot-settings. Visible foot/hand whiff actions replicate even without ball/player contact, player-hit ranges/cones are forgiving for live fighting, and client character visuals smooth render position/yaw/velocity before animation to reduce sideways movement and ragdoll flicker.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.031 environment props replace small procedural dressing with local Free3D instances baked to textureless Vertex PBR before scene insertion. Free3D environment meshes must have zero runtime texture maps, COLOR_0 alpha AO, uv1 roughness/metalness, and local client-visual rigid bodies/colliders/mass exposed through data-free3d-environment-* QA counters. Shared/server-authoritative prop physics is not yet shipped.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.035 textureless asset correction makes baked vertex/PBR data a hard gate: client/public/assets/{characters,environment,balls} must contain no image texture files, shipped GLBs must have zero images/textures/material texture refs and baked COLOR_0, Free3D character GLBs must also have packed TEXCOORD_1 roughness/metalness, and embedded-texture AutoRig GLBs are excluded from CHARACTER_ROSTER until converted. Deleting textures without baking vertex color is a blocker.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.036+ stamina drains only from Shift sprint and incoming player-hit damage. Space jump, LMB/RMB attacks, and whiffs must never spend attacker stamina or block recovery; playerStaminaJumpCost/playerStaminaHitCost stay clamped to zero in admin settings; acceptance must prove gradual sprint drain, zero-cost jump/whiff, and one-hit target knockout.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.040 exposes bot runtime health through /api/health, /api/game-settings, /api/bot-settings, and browser QA datasets: active bot count, visible bot count, hidden active player count, runtime bot enablement, target fill, human clients, and test-mode state must be inspectable without guessing.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.041 moves HTTP fallback stale-player cleanup into runtime settings as httpClientStaleMs, exposes it through /api/health, and uses the setting so closed/frozen HTTP clients release active slots back to bots after 12 seconds by default.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.042 adds websocketClientStaleMs to runtime settings and health, removes frozen WebSocket clients before bot fill, exposes desiredBotPlayers/nonBotActiveSlots/botFillSuppressionReason, and lets the client retry normal connection flow after WebSocket disconnect when auto-reconnect is enabled.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.043 makes off-ball fighting more reliable: RMB/head input counters are consumed only after an accepted strike or visible action, airborne LMB dash contributes swept player-hit reach when it misses the ball, and stamina still drains only from Shift plus incoming full-hit damage.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.044 makes bot fill self-heal during normal server ticks, requires bot combat to apply the same one-hit ragdoll knockout as human combat, makes possessed balls drop ownership and rebound when they collide with another player, keeps LMB possession-shot input alive until cooldown accepts it, and gates off-ball player hits by vertical reach so strikes do not damage unreachable targets.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.045 aligns bot combat with the free-attack stamina economy: low-stamina bots can still strike while not exhausted or ragdolling, one hit still fully knocks out targets, and ten-bot fill must remain stable through combat recovery.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.049 hardens the release gate for stamina, combat, and bots: acceptance must assert default friendly fire, one-hit knockout, zero jump cost, zero attacker hit cost, free head whiffs, and a separate non-test local server with testMode=false plus unsuppressed ten-bot fill.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.050 makes WebSocket leave/backfill explicit: browser pagehide sends /api/leave for WebSocket and HTTP players, /api/leave removes WebSocket players and closes their channel, and default websocketClientStaleMs is 12000 so stale human slots stop hiding bots quickly. Airborne LMB dash-kicks have wider swept player-hit reach for reliable jump knockouts. Exhausted standing players cannot own/capture the ball; high-aggression bots can finish exhausted opponents into ragdoll, while default bot combat pressure stays gated above the default aggression so bot-only football matches do not collapse.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.051 lets default-aggression bots visibly brawl again without breaking bot fill. botCombatAggressionThreshold, botCombatCollapseGuardRatio, and botCombatCollapseGuardMinDisabled live in game-settings.json and the admin schema, and acceptance proves one-hit bot knockout, stable bot ids, active bot fill, and no fill suppression.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.052 fixes point-blank no-ball strikes so overlap-range LMB/RMB contacts apply the same one-hit stamina knockout and ragdoll knockback as visible strikes. Acceptance also validates active bot ids, roles, finite playable-area positions, non-test human join backfill, and LMB+Shift possession shots with Shift remaining a strong-shot modifier.</rule>
    <rule>Local browser play servers must run without UNSOCCER_TEST_MODE. Test mode is only for isolated acceptance and intentionally prevents normal default bot fill unless /api/test/bots enables it.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.032 introduces unsoccer/game-settings.json as the runtime settings source, /api/game-settings plus /api/game-settings/reload as the authoritative apply/reload API, ServerState.settings/settingsRevision for client runtime tuning, and client/public/game-admin.html as the compact schema-driven admin page with controls/status metrics; client/public/game-settings.html remains the larger legacy admin surface. Every new UnSoccer gameplay, world, bot, audio, camera, lighting, prop, or UI feature that adds a tunable value must add it to GameSettings, DEFAULT_GAME_SETTINGS, GAME_SETTINGS_SCHEMA, game-settings.json, and the admin page contract in the same change. The settings admin is Russian-facing, GAME_SETTINGS_SCHEMA must cover every JSON/defaults key, and acceptance must prove per-key apply/readback through /api/game-settings.</rule>
    <rule>v0.0.033 adds player communication and personalization: a local-only 9-emotion mouse-wheel selector above the local player, replicated applied emotions in PlayerSnapshot.emotion, compact bottom-right chat, profile controls for nickname/skin/userPic across WebSocket and HTTP fallback, and server-authored body-side combat metadata where hand punches alternate right/left and LMB foot kicks use the current trailingFoot exposed through lastActionSide/trailingFoot/stancePhase.</rule>
    <rule>Server-confirmed left-foot, hand, head, jump, and body contacts must stay visually distinguishable and expose data-last-action-kind, data-last-action-player, and data-last-action-at for QA.</rule>
    <rule>Server owns physics, score, teams, and room assignment.</rule>
    <rule>Production transport is plain WebSocket JSON under /unsoccer/socket/ with HTTP polling fallback, implemented with built-in Node http/net/crypto primitives; do not require geckos.io, ws, or native node-datachannel on the Qwertystock host.</rule>
    <rule>UNSOCCER_TEST_MODE enables /api/test/* only for isolated local acceptance and must not be exposed in production.</rule>
    <rule>npm run test:unsoccer:acceptance is the deterministic gate for spectator roles, team-relative WASD movement, smoothed keyboard axes/acceleration, HTTP fallback join/input/state, pitch-bound freedom, foot/hand/head kicks, jump, sprint/stamina, weather, goal reset, and server audioEvents.</rule>
    <rule>Acceptance derives the expected version from package.json.games.unsoccer.version and must not hard-code a release string.</rule>
    <rule>npm run package:unsoccer rebuilds before creating dist/unsoccer-itch.zip so stale dist output is not published.</rule>
    <rule>Client audio is procedural Web Audio driven by authoritative ServerState audioEvents and weather state, not local input prediction.</rule>
    <rule>Audio QA must inspect data-audio-played-events, data-audio-blocked-events, data-audio-context, and data-audio-unlocked after a real trusted browser gesture.</rule>
    <rule>Humans/test clients get active-slot priority; server bots fill remaining active slots up to the active max in GameSettings, while clients beyond the active limit remain spectators/testers.</rule>
    <rule>Itch package contains static built client only.</rule>
    <rule>Free3D runtime assets require local GLB files and provenance; tokenless LowPoly 1k assets must be selected only from exact public worker inventory paths.json entries.</rule>
    <rule>Character ids in shared/src/index.ts CHARACTER_ROSTER must exist in client/public/assets/characters/free3d/roster.json with local textureless GLB and FBX clips before they can be assigned by the server.</rule>
    <rule>AutoRig task character provenance must record the task page, task API metadata, animations.glb source, locked bundle/download status, and prepared local FBX preview clips, but embedded-texture AutoRig GLBs must not ship in runtime until converted to textureless vertex/PBR.</rule>
  </rules>
</folderSkill>
